Mike Gilson

gilsoncoding@gmail.com | (206) 618-3263 |Seattle, WA LinkedIn: mikegilsonsoftdev | Github: ZenSorcere

CAREER SUMMARY

Completed the Web Development Certificate program at Seattle Central in Summer of 2020 and currently enrolled in North Seattle College's Application Development BAS program. Previously worked in the tech and gaming industries for 10+ years in Quality Assurance, as a tester and Test Lead, as well as in project/program management.

SKILLS

- Programming/Scripting Languages: Java, Python, SQL, JavaScript, PHP
- Frameworks/Libraries: Django, JUnit, Node.js, React
- Databases/Dev Tools: HTML, CSS, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Git version control
- Knowledge Areas: Agile Development, Kanban, JIRA, Confluence, CI/CD, System Testing, Cloud (AWS/Google Cloud), MS Office, G-Suite, Test Driven Development, Project Management

EDUCATION

North Seattle College (Fall 2020, Expected Graduation: Spring 2022)

Application Development BAS Program

 2020-2021 Coursework: Project Management in Software Development, Web and Mobile Application Development, Relational DB technology

Seattle Central College (2019 - 2020)

Web Development Certificate Program (GPA: 4.0/4.0)

- Phi Theta Kappa | Dean's List, President's List (4 times each)
- Coursework: HTML, CSS, Java, Data Structures & Algorithms, JavaScript, jquery, node.js, APIs, PHP, SQL, Django, Systems Analysis, Object-oriented Design, Relational Databases, Database Design, Database Admin

University of Washington (1992-1997)

B.A Drama (GPA: 3.16/4.0)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Easy-Ware Corporation | Freelance | CSS Consultant

09/2020 - 10/2020

- Create responsive css design solutions for newly created non-profit partner organization ticketing and fundraising pages.
- Worked with Project Manager and Development Team to implement cross-organization global css improvements, resulting in increased page completion rates.

• Analyzed issues encountered with new pages and container types to establish and document process for page html/css setup to ensure uniformity in future page creation.

<u>SitePro Solutions | Crown Castle | Project Manager, Arch&Eng Specialist</u> 07/2017 - 03/2019

- Coordinate and expedite construction drawing production, including pricing/contracting
 with vendors, quality control of initial drawings, coordinating with carrier, managing
 changes/revisions, and ensuring construction drawings match accordingly.
- Executed workflow process enhancements to establish customer product specialization and vendor priority, reducing drawing completion time by 20%.

Nordstrom | Interactive Development DevOps | Program Manager I, Test 07/2015 - 11/2016

- Implemented a Kanban workflow to track additional Test team tasks, resulting in improved capacity insight and resource tracking.
- Analyzed browser usage data trends using Tableau to refine and improve dev/testing efficiency, resulting in improved test focus and increased deployment speed 15%.
- Developed and executed a new process and schedule for all required Test documentation, including a ground-up restructure of the Team's Confluence organization, resulting in reduced production issues and greatly improved transparency.

Nordstrom | Interactive Development DevOps | Front End Test Lead 03/2012 - 07/2015

- Improved established workflow processes by dedicating time to each work focus area for training, immersion, and proficiency development, and removing bottlenecks due to siloed skillsets, resulting in increased test team efficiency.
- Analyzed team workload capacity to optimize weekly build sizes, and forecast future capacity impacts, which became the standard for all future build work, resulting in 60% reduction in post-build launch fixes and better customer experience.

ScreenLife, LLC | SceneIT? Brand Games | Software Tester 03/2005 - 03/2012

 Designed and maintained test case matrices and documentation for use on all Screenlife titles, resulting in reduced test time, decreased beta releases, and additional capacity for Design and Authoring teams, improving product release times.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Active member in Seattle's Fringe Theater community 01/2009 - Present

 Long-time volunteer staff member at Annex Theatre. Experience working with limited budgets and resources, creative problem solving, experience in communicating thoughts and ideas to diverse groups, and working in collaborative team environments to drive toward project completion.